Contact

2701 North Decatur Road Decatur, Georgia 30033 (432) 559-2911 (Mobile) bob.dent@emoryhealthcare.or g

www.linkedin.com/in/bobdent (LinkedIn) www.emoryhealthcare.org (Company)

Top Skills

Strategic Planning Healthcare Hospitals

Certifications

Fellow in the American Academy of Nursing (FAAN)

Nurse Executive Advanced - Board Certified (NEA-BC)

Fellow, American Organization for Nursing Leadership (formerly AONE)

Fellow American College of Healthcare Executives (FACHE)

Certified Executive in Nursing Practice (CENP)

Honors-Awards

2014 Distinguished Alumni Award 2016 Richard Hader Visionary Leader Award

2013 Excellence in Leadership Award

2010 Healthcare Leadership Award Class of 2006 Up and Comer of the Year

Publications

Nine Principles for Improved Nurse Staffing

ANA White Paper: Optimal Nurse Staffing to Improve Quality of Care and Outcomes

Dr. Bob Dent, FACHE, FAAN, FAONL

Vice President, Chief Nursing Officer at Emory Healthcare Decatur

Summary

Provide executive level leadership and support for various nursing and operational departments within the hospital. Strategic-oriented senior level healthcare executive with more than 30 years of progressive leadership experience gained in acute care hospitals, long-term care, and academia. Well-rounded background with success in leading all aspects of hospital operations, strategic planning, leadership development, cultural transformation, and new business development. Possesses solid relationship management, positive communication, and business acumen to achieve excellent outcomes.

Experience

Emory Healthcare Vice President, Chief Nursing Officer August 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) Decatur, Georgia

Vice President, Chief Nursing Officer for three hospitals, Emory Decatur Hospital, Emory Hillandale Hospital, and Emory Long Term Acute Care Hospital.

American Organization for Nursing Leadership 6 years 8 months

Past President

January 2014 - Present (6 years 8 months)

2020-present: Past President, AONL Board of Directors

2019: Immediate Past President, AONL Board of Directors

2018: President AONE Board of Directors

Contributing Author to The Advisory Boards 2015 Research

How to Improve Hospital Operations and Patient Safety in 14 minutes a Day

American Hospital Association Value Initiative Case Study: Predictive Analytics Creates Value through nurse staffing system.

2017: President-Elect AONE Board of Directors

2014-2016: Elected to represent nurse executives & leaders from Region 7 (Texas, Arkansas, Louisiana, Oklahoma) to the AONE. The work with this great group of thought leaders is amazing.

- # American Hospital Association (AHA) Regional Policy Board (RPB) ad hoc member 2014-2016.
- # Immediate Past Chair, Foundation Board of Directors, 2016.
- # Co-chair, Foundation Development Advisory Group, 2016.
- # Chair, Annual Meeting Committee, 2016.
- # Chair, Abstract Review Committee, 2016.
- # Chair, Foundation Board of Directors, 2015.
- # Chair, Foundation Development Advisory Group, 2015.
- # Chair, Taskforce: Nurse Executive Competencies to Lead Population Health in the Future, 2015.
- # Vice Chair, Foundation Board, 2014.
- # Co-Chair, Taskforce: Nurse Executive Competencies for Post Acute Care, 2014.

Foundation Board Chair

November 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 2 months)

Greater Chicago Area

- ~Vice Chair 2014
- ~Chair. AONE Foundation 2015
- ~Past Chair, AONE Foundation 2016

For those interested in donating to this foundation to further provide grants and education to advance nursing leadership, please do not hesitate.

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center

9 years 1 month

Adjunct Faculty School of Nursing

August 2011 - Present (9 years 1 month)

Have assisted in teaching in the Doctorate of Nursing Practice program

National Advisory Board Member

September 2015 - Present (5 years)

The TTUHSC National Advisory Board members serve in an advisory role to the president, deans and executive director of the TTUHSC Alumni Association on matters like alumni engagement, higher education, healthcare education, and respective specialty practice areas. Additionally, we will:

- ~Identify prospective board members
- ~Identify nominees for the TTUHSC Distinguished Alumni Awards and the Emerging Professionals Academy
- ~Serve as a mentor and career coach for TTUHSC students and new graduates

American College of Healthcare Executives 22 years

Fellow ACHE 2007 - Present (13 years)

Member 1998 - Present (22 years)

Values Coach Advisory Board Member August 2015 - Present (5 years 1 month)

Joe Tye has created an Advisory Board to assist him and the Values Coach team to:

- ~ Best define the business
- ~ Website and social media presence
- ~ Effectively reach broader audience
- ~ Improving relationships
- ~ Capitalizing on the strengths of Joe Tye and Values Coach

UT Permian Basin Adjunct Professor November 2014 - July 2019 (4 years 9 months) Odessa/Midland, Texas Area

I facilitate the Nursing Leadership & Management Synthesis & Reasoning course with the 4th semester BSN students.

Midland Memorial Hospital
Senior Vice President, Chief Operating & Chief Nursing Officer
January 2007 - July 2019 (12 years 7 months)
Page 3 of 6

Midland, Texas

Vice President, Chief Nursing Officer 2007-2009

Vice President, Patient Care Services & Chief Nursing Officer 2009-2014

Senior Vice President, Chief Operating Officer 2014-2015

Senior Vice President, Chief Operating Officer & Chief Nursing Officer 2016
present

Midland Memorial Hospital, located in Midland, Texas, is a 464-bed hospital operating out of approximately 250 beds with an average daily census of 180. We have approximately 60,000 emergency room visits and 2,500 births per year. We recently formed Midland Health as we continue to grow our ambulatory presence in the greater Midland area.

University of Phoenix

Executive Advisory Board Member, Center for Healthcare Research in the School of Advanced Studies

June 2015 - December 2018 (3 years 7 months)

Creating a scholar-practitioner driven center of excellence in applied healthcare research. Our research will NOT be clinical. Instead, it will focus on the business, data analytics, management, operations, and strategic dimension of the healthcare and lifescience sectors. We will pursue applied, relevant, and timely research.

Midland YMCA
Board Member
September 2013 - August 2016 (3 years)
Odessa/Midland, Texas Area

Provide guidance to the leadership to meet the mission of the Midland YMCA.

AONE

Member 2002 - June 2016 (14 years)

Past member of the Nominating Committee

Texas Organization of Nurse Executives Board Member

AONE Professional Practice Policy Committee Member

AONE Strategic Planning Committee, 2 years

Midland College
Dean, Health Sciences Division
December 2012 - July 2014 (1 year 8 months)
Midland, Texas

I have added responsibilities to my current role with Midland Memorial Hospital as the Dean, Health Sciences Division. This division consists of the ADN, VN, Respiratory Therapy, EMS, Paramedic, HIT, Fire Science, SimLife Center and Radiology Sonography programs. I look to continue to bridge the relationship between MC and MMH as well as the Academic-Practice environments.

Texas Team

Practice Committee Member
January 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 8 months)

I represent West Texas Hospitals on the Texas Team Practice Committee working to implement the four key suggestions and eight recommendations of the Institute of Medicine and Robert Wood Johnson Foundation Report on the Future of Nursing.

Texas Organization of Nurse Executives

Board Member

September 2008 - September 2012 (4 years 1 month)

Serving on the board for TONE is a great experience. Being able to shape the landscape for nursing practice and leadership. Working with leaders across the state of Texas was wonderful.

American Organization of Nurse Executives Strategic Planning Committee

January 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Assigned to this team for two years to help create the strategic plan for AONE. It was a great experience working with leaders across the country.

Texas Nurses Association

Practice Committee Member

January 2008 - May 2010 (2 years 5 months)

Chair of the TNA Practice Committee 2009-2010. From my time on this committee came the Fatigue Management Policy created and implemented at Midland Memorial Hospital. This has made a difference with our staff. There were many opportunities to assist with legislative issues that would affect nursing practice. A very good experience.

Banner Health

14 years

Chief Nursing Officer 2005 - 2007 (2 years)

Sterling, Colorado

Long Term Care Administrator February 1998 - March 2005 (7 years 2 months)

Mesa, Arizona

Responsibilities included administrator for the 180 hospital-based long term care facility. Banner Desert Care Center was recognized as the "Best of the Best" at Banner Desert Medical Center for scorecard outcomes. The subacute unit was 60-beds with high volume.

Registered Nurse
August 1993 - February 1998 (4 years 7 months)
Critical Care
Assistant Director of Nursing, Skilled Nursing
Director of Nursing, Skilled Nursing

Methodist Hospital Registered Nurse August 1989 - August 1993 (4 years 1 month) LVN and RN, Critical Care

Education

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center DNP, Doctorate Nursing Practice · (2008 - 2010)

University of Phoenix MBA, Health Care Management · (2002 - 2004)

University of Phoenix BSN, Nursing (1996 - 1998)

South Plains College

Associates Degree in Applied Sciences, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1990 - 1992)

Texas State Technical College-West Texas Vocational Nursing, Nursing · (1988 - 1989)